Guide to the Building Trades Employers Association Records WAG.196
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Contracts, 1903-1993; 9 Linear Feet 9 Record Cartons
  - Contracts- Sheet Metal Worker and Employers, 1960-1966 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Contracts- Sheet Metal Worker and Employers, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Contracts- Sheet Metal Worker and Employers, 1971-1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Contracts- Sheet Metal Worker and Employers, 1985-1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers, 1926-1929 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers, 1930-1942 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers with Heating Contracts, 1936-1947 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers with Heating Contracts, 1950-1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers with Heating Contracts, 1966-1975 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers with Heating Contracts, 1975-1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Contracts- Steamfitters and Helpers with Heating Contracts, 1984-1990 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Contracts- Stone Setters and Employ'g Stone Set, 1925-1947 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Contracts- Stone Setters and Employ'g Stone Set, 1950-1962 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Contracts- Stone Setters and Employ'g Stone Set, 1964-1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Contracts- Stone Cutters and Employers Machine Stone Workers, 1923-1930 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Contracts- Stone Cutters and Employers Machine Stone Workers, 1932-1940 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Contracts- Stone Cutters and Employers Machine Stone Workers, 1940-1948 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Contracts- Stone Cutters and Employers Machine Stone Workers, 1950-1989 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Contracts- Stone Masons and Contractors (old), 1916-1950 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1941-1948 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1950-1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1965-1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Contracts- Structural Steel Workers, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1972-1978 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1939-1948 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1948-1953 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Contracts- Teamsters, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Contracts- Temporary Elevator Operators, 1960-1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Contracts- Temporary Elevator Operators, 1973-1981 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Contracts- Temporary Elevator Operators, 1981-1990 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Contracts- Tile Layers and Helpers and Tile Co., 1926-1942 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Contracts- Tile Layers and Helpers and Tile Co, 1947-1958 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Contracts- Tile Layers and Helpers and Tile Co, 1960-1964 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Contracts- Tile Layers and Helpers and Tile Co, 1967-1979 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Contracts- Tile Layers and Helpers and Tile Co, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Contracts- Tile Layers and Helpers and Tile Co, 1979-1991 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Contracts- Timberman, 1941 and 1969 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Contracts- Upholsters Agreement (Record Only), 1925-1968 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Contracts- Woodworkers (Old), 1915-1950 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Series II: Mediations, Arbitrations, and Correspondence, circa 1903-1995; 35 Linear Feet 35 Record Cartons
  - Agreement* Allied Building Metal Industries and Building Trades Council Order on Laborers (Dioguardi Organization), 1921-1922 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Building Trade Council Agreement and Modification, Nov 20, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Building Trades Council Constitution and By-laws Building and Construction Trades Council Constitution and By-laws, 1922-1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bldg. Trades Council Agreement and Letter, May 17-Jun 16 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Building Trades Council, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Certificate of Copyright Registration- Handbook & "The Shortened Workday", 1930-1950 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - George Contos- Deceased Employee (Kitchen), 1944 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - List of Association Secretaries- Unions Who Signed Arbitrations Plan, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Mechanics & Trades Exchange & Beta Agreement Charter & By-law, 1909-1933 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Samuel Untermeyr's Plan and Agrument against It, Building Trades Council Agreement, 1922-Aug 12, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Trustees- Various Pension Funds Engineers W&P Fund, 1968-1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Twelve Principles- Minutes of Executive Committee Meeting, Oct. 9, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Trust Co. Custodian Account, Improvement & Betterment, 1938; 1957 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Mediations (Box 11)
  - Mediations (Box 12)
  - Mediations (Box 13)
  - Mediations (Box 14)
  - Mediations (Box 15)
  - Arbitrations: 1 to 19-2a (Box 16)
  - Arbitrations: 19-3a to 24 (Box 17)
  - Arbitrations: 24 to 37d (Box 18)
  - Arbitrations: 37f to 60a (Box 19)
  - Arbitrations: 60a to 71a (Box 20)
  - Arbitrations: 72 to 84-2b (Box 21)
    Scope and Content Note
    The collections contains contracts (arranged by name of union), mediation and arbitration files (arranged by case number), minutes of the BTEA (available on microfilm), correspondence, and a small number of photographs, newsletters and clippings.
    Arrangement
    Collection is mostly unprocessed; files are in original order.
    Provenance
    The records were donated to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives in May 1999 by the Building Trades Employers Association, under an agreement with its Chairman, Louis J. Colletti.
  - Arbitrations: 84b-84-2b to 100h (Box 22)
  - Arbitrations: 100h to 129-ja (Box 23)
  - Arbitrations: 130 to 143-a (Box 24)
  - Arbitrations: 143-a to 160-3a (Box 25)
  - Arbitrations: 156 to 165 (Box 26)
  - Arbitrations: 165a to 173 (Box 27)
  - Arbitrations: 174 to 184-5b (Box 28)
  - Arbitrations: 184-5b-211-b (Box 29)
  - Arbitrations: 211-3b to 212-3f (Box 30)
  - Arbitrations: 212-3f to 230 (Box 31)
  - Arbitrations: 230-a to 244-3d (Box 32)
  - Arbitrations: 244-4d to 260a (Box 33)
  - Arbitrations: 260-3a to 269-7c (Box 34)
  - Arbitrations: 269-7c to 282 and Other Materials (Box 35)
  - BTEA Minutes and Convention (Amendments), 1903; 1907-1929 (Box 36)
  - BTEA Minutes, 1937-1955 (Box 37)
  - Special Agreements and Agreements with those not members of BTEA, 1906-1976 (Box 38)
  - Minutes-Executive Board, 1971-1994 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, Arbitration and General Files (Box 40)
  - Correspondence, Arbitration and General Files (Box 41)
  - Correspondence, Arbitration and General Files (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, Arbitration and General Files (Box 43)
  - Correspondence, Arbitration and General Files (Box 44)
  - Photos, Newsletters and Clippings, 1937-1975 (Box 45)
- Series III: Mediations and Arbitrations: 2013 Accession, 1989-2011; 2000-2011; 2013.024; 11 Linear Feet 11 Record cartons
  Materials in this series have not been rearranged, but boxes have been renumbered to be included in the rest of the collection. Boxes are listed roughly in chronological order and materials within boxes contain a semblance of chronology, although it is not entirely consistent.
  Series 3 was added to the collection in 2013 and contains mediation and arbitration files created between 1989 and 2011. The boxes labeled "Arbitrations" contain bound transcprits, many of which are accompanied by three ring binders of official evidence. Mediation files are less formal and contain a wide range of documentation including, court papers, correspondence, and evidence relating to each suit. Please note that boxes labeled "Mediation" may also contain arbitrations as many disputes initially intended to be resolved as mediations ultimately ended in arbitration.
  - Arbitrations/Mediations, assorted documents, 1989-2005 (Box 46)
    Mediation and Arbitration files mostly created before 2000. Also contains notes, statistics, and contact information created around 2003-3005.
  - Arbitrations: 01-01-00 to 28-11-01, 2000-2001 (Box 47)
  - Mediations: 01-01-00 to 44-01-02, 2000-2002 (Box 48)
  - Arbitrations: 34-05-01 to 79-08-03, 2001-2003 (Box 49)
  - Mediations: 46-02-02 to 63-11-02, 2002 (Box 50)
  - Mediations: 80-07-03 to 109-07-05, 2003-2005 (Box 51)
  - Arbitrations: 110-07-05 to 125-06, 2005-2006 (Box 52)
  - Mediations: 110-07-05 to 129-08-06, 2005-2006 (Box 53)
  - Mediations: 139-01-07 to 200-07-09, 2007-2009 (Box 54)
  - Arbitrations: 2007-2010 (Not Numbered) (Box 55)
  - Mediations: 187-12-08 to 241-8-8-11, 2008-2011 (Box 56)
- Series IV: Group Portraits, circa 1897-1906 (Box Tamiment Shared OS006, Folder 1)
  Photographs, as well as photocopies with captions, of the Board of Delegates and Board of Governors of the Building Trades Employers Association.
- Series V: Archived Website, Feb 1, 2009-ongoing
  Building Trades Employers Association (BTEA) is affiliated with 28 trade union contractor associations, representing the 1,700 construction managers, general contractors and specialty subcontractor firms in New York City, who employ 125,000 people. Members range in size from multi-billion dollar internationally recognized firms to small and mid-sized specialty trade contracting firms. The BTEA promotes safety, skill training, professional standards, and works to strengthen the economic vitality and social fabric of New York City. The website contains event listings, reports and publications, including the BTEA News, training and committee information, bargaining agreement schedules, and information on their current projects.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.